Guide to the Planned Parenthood of Houston & Southeast Tex. Records
University of Houston Libraries
- Affiliated Organizations with Planned Parenthood of Houston and Southeast Texas, id103685
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America “Insider” newsletter, Jun 1990 – Jan 1991, Sept 1992; id109152 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Planned Parenthood Review, Vol #6, Issue #1 Winter 1986, Vol #3, Issue #3 Fall 1983``, id109153 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Planned Parenthood of North Texas, id109155 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Correspondence and Press Releases, Oct 16, 2001 – Dec 11, 2002; id109156 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Photographic Material, id109157 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, 1980 – 1993; id109158 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, Feb – Mar 1998; id109159 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, Apr. – Jun 1998; id109160 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, Sep – Dec 1998; id109161 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, 1999; id109162 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, 2002; id109163 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station Newspaper Clippings, undated; id109164 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Abortion and birth control related publications, id109165 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - “Family planning perspectives” Vol. 4, No. 1:, Jan 1972; id109166 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Citizens for parenthood by choice, id109167 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - TARAL (Texas abortion rights action league) newsletter, id109168 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - “National Voter” League of Women Voters, Jun/July 1989; id109169 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Feminist majority report, 1990; id109170 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - NARAL (National abortion rights action league), id109171 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - NOW (National Organization for Women), id109172 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Population action council, id109173 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - National Audubon Society, id109174 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Population Communications International, id109175 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Population options, id109176 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Population Reference Bureau, id109177 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Population-Environment Balance, Inc., id109178 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Population-Environment Balance, Inc. (Balance reports), id109179 (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
  - Governmental Reports, NGOs, UN, UNICEF, Jan 1975 – May 1989; id109181 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Population Institute, Jan 1978 - Dec 1986; id109182 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Population Institute, Jul 1987 – Dec 1988; id109183 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Population Institute, March 1989, Unknown dates; id109184 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Zero Population Growth – correspondence, 1971 – 1988; id109185 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Zero Population Growth, 1970 – 1973; id109186 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Zero Population Growth, 1975 – 1989; id109187 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Zero Population Growth, undated; id109188 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Various population publications and organizations, March 1971 – April 1989; id109189 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - OVS periodicals:, id109191 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Swarts, Kathryn. “One person at a time.” West U. Magazine. Sept 1992. (Planned Parenthood article) 24-27., id109196 (Box 10, Folder 1, Item 1)
    - Simon, Susan. “56 years of planning and principles.” River Oaks magazine. Sept. 1992. 18 – 21, id109197 (Box 10, Folder 1, Item 2)
    - Aggieland Primer– various advertisements for the Bryan Planned Parenthood, id109198 (Box 10, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - OVS Zero population growth, 1978 - 1981; id109192 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - OVS Zero Population growth, 1982 –1989; id109193 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - OVS populations, March 1971 – April 1989; id109194 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - OVS Popline – world population news service, April 1981 – August 1989; id109195 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Planned Parenthood Newspaper Clippings, id103686
  The following series is contained in 2 boxes and contains 32 folders. Planned Parenthood of Houston and Southeast Texas employees and volunteers maintained an extensive file of newspaper clippings on interests and concerns of relevance to Planned Parenthood’s social and political missions. The series is arranged in two sub-series, the first being the undated original clippings which are arranged thematically. The second sub-series are the files Planned Parenthood employees and volunteers maintained with photocopies of relevant articles which were used for education and public outreach. The clippings range from 1936 – 2001.
  - Original Clippings, id103689
    - Abortion, 1950 – 1979; id109200 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Miriam Kass “Houston Post” abortion series, 1970; id109201 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Abortion, 1980- 1989; id109202 (Box 7, Folder 3-6)
    - Roe vs. Wade, id109206 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Planned Parenthood related clippings, id109207 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - History of birth control movement, id109209 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Birth control methods, id109210 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Family planning and world population - international, id109211 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Population clippings, 1972 – 1987; id109212 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Population clippings, 1987-1989; id109213 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Population clippings, undated; id109214 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Family, marriage, pregnancy and social issues, id109215 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Poverty – social issues, id109216 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Sex education and teen Pregnancy, id109217 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - U.S. politics, id109218 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - OVS Newspaper pages 1938, 1970-1989, id109220 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood Office/Library copies of newspaper clippings, id103690
    - 1936-1953, id109222 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - 1954 – 1959, id109223 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - 1960 – 1969, id109224 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - 1970 – 1979, id109225 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - 1980 – 1986, id109226 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - 1987 – 1989, id109227 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 1992, id109228 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - 1993, id109229 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - 1994, id109230 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - 1995, id109231 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - 1996, id109232 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - 1997- 1998, id109233 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Scrap Books, id103687
  This series is contained in 3 boxes and has 8 folders, with dates ranging from 1940 – 2001. Planned Parenthood of Houston and Southeast Texas and other affiliated branches of Planned Parenthood created several scrapbooks featuring events and news of importance to Planned Parenthood. Of particular interest is a scrapbook with photographs and newspaper articles dating from the 1940s and 1950s.
  - Clippings, 2001; id109235 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1940s and 1950s; id109236 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Planned Parenthood of Bryan/College Station scrapbook, id109237 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook copies, 1940s and 1950s; id109238 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - OVS scrapbook originals, 1950s; id109240 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - OVS scrapbook copies, 1950s; id109242 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - OVS Fort Bend scrapbook, originals and copies, id109243 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - OVS Unidentified scrapbook pages, id109245 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Planned Parenthood through the years exhibit displays, id103688
  This series is contained in 2 boxes and features exhibit displays prepared by Planned Parenthood of Houston and Southeast Texas to chronicle their history and growth as an organization. The displays are organized by year and range from 1940 – 2000.
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 1940s; id109247 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 1950s; id109248 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 1960s; id109249 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 1970s; id109250 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 1980s; id109252 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 1990s; id109253 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Planned Parenthood through the years, 2000; id109254 (Box 12, Folder 3)